A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Log Files (Grant and Project Proposals) FA734
Rockefeller Archive Center
- 1957
  - L57-177: Program of studies involving an electronic brain (W. Ross Ashby), 1957 (Reel L-26)
    See also Log file L57-144: Staff study of the computing machine field; and grant file 05700090 (PA57-90), Carnegie Mellon University, SUMMER SEMINAR IN NEW DEVELOPMENTS IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION.
  - L57-181: Southeast Asian public administration conference, Institute of Public Administration, University of the Philippines, 1957 (Reel L-26)
  - L57-182: International project on human origins, Columbia University (Dr. Helmut de Terra), 1957 (Reel L-26)
  - L57-185: Support for the Universal Spiritual Alliance (Marko Zuzic), 1957 (Reel L-26)
  - L57-193: Economic and social effects of automation, Labor and Industrial Relations Center, Michigan State University (Charles C. Killingsworth), 1957 (Reel L-26)
  - L57-197: Study of development in legal education - Ford Foundation, 1957 (Reel L-26, Reel L-27)
    See also Log files: L60-900: Creation of a civic law office in a number of law schools (Ford Foundation); and L63-854: Survey of education concerning law, with special emphasis on the professional schools of law and the administration of justice in relation to social problems and public affairs (Ford Foundation).
  - L57-200: Study of the morale and unionization of American engineers, Loyola University, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-201: Work with medical students, placement service, and hospitals - Virginia Council on Health and Medical Care, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-204: Student load fund, State of New York (William J. Embler), 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-205: Support for Santa Fe College of Liberal Arts (James P. Speer), 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-206: Dr. Ludwig Erhard, Minister of Economic Affairs of West Germany, lecture at Columbia University (Courtney C. Brown), 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-209: Handling of the Burmese rice crop by the Burmese marketing authority (Edwin G. Arnold, Ford Foundation, Burma), 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-211: Philip Locklin study on transportation problems in Australia, New Zealand, and Indonesia, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-212: Study of authority on supervisory levels in public administration, University of Chicago (Peter M. Blau), 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-214: Research in child development, National Child Research Center (Richard K. Lyon), 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-220: Support to the World Friendship Federation (Arthur McTaggart Short), 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-225: Research on children, International Children's Centre, Paris, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-230: Moral rearmament movement, Wilson Compton, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-239: Preparatory survey for a study on communications through symbols, Rudolf Modley, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-244: Public health institute in Panama, Ventures Limited, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-246: Research project on mental retardation in children, Children's Hospital of Los Angeles, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-248: Postgraduate studies for students from underdeveloped countries, London School of Economics and Political Science, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-250: Research fund in low cost housing technology, United Nations, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-251: India International Legal Studies - Ford Foundation, 1957 (Reel L-27)
    See also L59-255: Ford Foundation support for projects in law -- India.
    Includes "Legal Studies in India" (1957), by Carl Spaeth and H.C.L. Merillat.
  - L57-254: Iona Foundation Ocho Rios, and Folk High School, Jamaica, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-255: Institute of Research and Study in Medieval Canon Law, Stephan Kuttner, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-256: Conference, Boston Regional Conference on NATO Affairs, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-258: American Music Center, Inc., Ernst Bacon, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-259: Young Christian Workers, Malta, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-260: Conservation Education Foundation of Maine, Inc., 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-261: Science Center Founding Committee, Inc., 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-264: Archive of information on craftsmen and artists of Texas, Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-265: Establishment of an Institute of Gerontology, University of Connecticut., 1957 (Reel L-27)
    See also related Ford Foundation grants on aging: PA57-5, PA58-131, PA58-255, PA58-256, PA58-290, PA58-384, PA58-397, PA58-354. See also Log files: L57-141: Staff study on the aging as a field for Ford Foundation interest; and L56-989: Support to the Senior Citizens of Santa Cruz, California.
  - L57-266: Program to develop interest in mathematics and engineering careers, Future Engineers of America, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-270: Election study, Foreign Service of the United States, American Embassy, Bonn, Germany, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-271: Documentary film on rural development in Burma - Ford Foundation field office, Rangoon, Burma, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-275: Research program to scientifically secure invaluable data relative to population growth of Chicago, J. Walter Thompson Company, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-283: Canada Council for the Arts, Humanities and Social Sciences, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-286: Evaluation of Germany cities under U.S. military government - Herman Kehrli, Bureau of Municipal Research and Service, University of Oregon, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-291: Self-survey project, University of Dayton, Ohio, 1957 (Reel L-27)
  - L57-292: Staff study on Program in Science and Engineering Education - Ford Founation, 1957 (Reel L-28)
    Includes material on C. Richard Soderberg (MIT).
  - L57-297: Facilitating student exchanges, Brittingham Foreign Scholarships Foundation, Inc., Thomas E. Brittingham, Jr., 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-298: Summer seminar on the teaching of public administration, George Washington University, Alfred G. Obern, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-299: Economic Abstracts (journal), Thomas L. Norton, New York University, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-300: World history book project, L.S. Stavrianos, Northwestern University, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-301: Research on identification and family structure, Urie Bronfenbrenner, Cornell University, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-302: Anglo-American Institute, H.C. Allen, University College London, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-303: Traffic Safety Association of Detroit, Donald Slutz, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-305: Cuttington College and Divinity School, Missionary District of Liberia, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-306: Air pollution and metropolitan growth, Lauren B. Hitchcock, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-307: Proposed new journal, Helen Hill Miller, National Publishing Company, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-309: Atomic energy research, Luke C.L. Yuan, Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-310: Request for fellowship, Mr. Mangunsarkoro - Ford Foundation field office, Jakarta, Indonesia, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-315: Technical education in Bangkok, Thailand - E.O. Sessions, United States of America Operations Mission, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-316: Anthropos (journal) and ethnographic field work, Rudolf Rahmann, Anthropos-Institut, Posieux, Fribourg, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-318: Study of regional variation in the countries of South Asia, W. Norman Brown, University of Pennsylvania, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-320: Environment Unlimited, organic world center, Stuart Kent Harper, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-330: Problem of two-year community colleges, Clifford P. Case, U.S. Senate, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-332: Completing the Thesaurus Linguae Latinae, Gilbert Highet, Columbia University, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-341: Staff study of national defense - Ford Foundation, 1957 (Reel L-29)
    See also L57-1136: Proposal for Mobilization Management Research Foundation, George A. Steiner.
  - L57-347: Support for exiled students of Technical University of Sopron, Hungary - National Representation of Free Hungary, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-350: Grant in Aid program for the 'best men' in the behavioral sciences - Ford Foundation, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-353: Survey of the effects of industrialization upon a tribal population in Sierra Leone, West Africa, Kenneth Little, Dept of Anthropology, University California Los Angeles, 1957 (Reel L-29)
  - L57-357: General support - William M. Milliken, American Association of Museums, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-358: Irish Institute of Public Administration, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-359: Study of disease patterns and geographical context, American Geographical Society, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-362: Study of industrial productivity, Seymour Melman, Columbia University, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-366: Journal of Public Affairs, George Graham and Kermit Gordon, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-367: Support for faculty research - Forrest McDonald, American History Research Center, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-368: Staff study on teaching of English as a second language - Ford Foundation, 1957 (Reel L-30)
    See also Ford Foundation grant 05700296 (PA57-296), National Academy of Sciences, Conference on teaching English as a second language.
  - L57-369: Scholarships for Polish students - Kosciuszko Foundation, American Center for Polish Culture, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-374: Establishment of a Center for Research and Training in Group Dynamics - Douglas Ensminger, Ford Foundation field office, New Delhi, India, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-376: Staff study on college building program - Ford Foundation, 1957 (Reel L-30)
    Includes "Report on Plant Needs in Private Colleges and Universities", 1956, by Milton Mackaye.
  - L57-377: Educational journalism - Association for Higher Education, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-380: Project for obtaining the sampling distribution of correlation coefficients from economic time series, Edward Ames, Purdue University, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-381: Research in processes of political socialization, David Easton, University of Chicago, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-385: Kermit Gordon - European trip to major centers of economic research and training in Britain and continental Europe, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-386: Armando Maglaque, Senior Economist, National Economic Council, Philippines, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-390: Archive of foreign policy documents from Poland and the Soviet Union, Stanislaw Mikolajczyk, 1957 (Reel L-30)
  - L57-398: Study of the influence of campus subcultures on students' value -systems, Edward W. Hazen Foundation, 1957 (Reel L-30, Reel L-31)
  - L57-399: Training in Hotel Administration (Michael Harris, Ford Foundation Representative in Indonesia), 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-402: University of Wisconsin, student exchange with universities in Poland, 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-408: Institute for Social Research, England - Social sciences in Europe, Cologne Institute, 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-413: American Symphony Orchestra League, Inc. - Music education program for school age children, 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-417: Print Council of America - quarterly magazine on the graphic arts, 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-426: Thunderbird Broadcasting Co., KGAK, Gallup, New Mexico - radio broadcasts in Navajo Indian language, 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-428: John M.H. Lindbeck - Asian Neutralism and the United States, 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-429: Lenox hill Neighborhood House, James M. Snowden, 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-430: United World Federalists, Inc. - film project, 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-431: Purdue Research Foundation -"Study of Certain Problems Arising in the Scheduling of University Classes", 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-434: Lisle Fellowship Inc. - Learning by doing, 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-435: University of Hawaii - Graduate scholarships in field related to food production for students from the countries of south and east Asia, 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-437: Program Specialist in Group Methods - Ford Foundation, New Delhi, India Field Office, 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-438: Otterbein College, Westerville, Ohio - audio-visual methods of teaching foreign languages, 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-439: Philharmonic-Symphony Society of New York - Young people's concerts for combined television and live audience, 1957 (Reel L-31)
  - L57-442: College Art Association Inc. - International gathering of scholars in Washington DC, 1957 (Reel L-31, Reel L-32)
    See also: Ford Foundation, Grant 05900169 (PA59-169), College Art Association Inc., Study of American Higher Education in the Visual Arts.
  - L57-446: City of New York - Study of technical and professional manpower requirements of the City of New York, 1957 (Reel L-32)
  - L57-447: Mediaeval Academy of America - Revised and enlarged edition of "Guide to the Study of Medieval History", 1957 (Reel L-32)
  - L57-457: Management Conference Board - international understanding, 1957 (Reel L-32)
  - L57-461: SOS-Kinderdorf (SOS-Children Village), Germany - Abandoned children, 1957 (Reel L-32)
  - L57-477: Project for Poland and Czechoslovakia - Ford Foundation, Shepard Stone, 1957 (Reel L-32, Reel L-33)
    See also: Ford Foundation, Grant 05700369 (PA57-369), University of Poznan (Poland), "PROVIDE SCHOLARLY AND SCIENTIFIC BOOKS, PERIODICALS AND EQUIPMENT FROM THE UNITED STATES AND EUROPE"; and Grant 05800103 (PA58-103), Cooperative for Assistance and Relief Everywhere Inc. (CARE), "ASSISTANCE IN PROVIDING BOOKS, PERIODICALS AND EQUIPMENT TO POLISH UNIVERSITIES".
  - L57-478: William H. Lewis - Support for Morocco, 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-479: Free Europe Committee - Proposed Institute of East European Affairs, 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-482: Hebrew Culture Foundation - Study of Hebrew Culture and Civilization of Modern Israel in American Institutions of Higher Learning, 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-483: Society for the Arts in America - magazine, 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-484: Youth Consultation Service, Episcopal Diocese of New York, Inc. - building, 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-485: Deutsche Hochschule Fur Politik (German Academy for Politics) - Support, Dr. Ernest Frainkel, 1957 (Reel L-33)
    See also Ford Foundation Grant 05800260 (PA58-260), Free University of Berlin, "GENERAL PROGRAM".
  - L57-486: Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton University - Study of Chief Justice John Marshall by Samuel J. Konefsky, 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-487: Museum of Modern Art - International Architectural Exhibition at the XI Triennale di Milano, 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-488: University of California, Los Angeles - Project Africa, 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-489: Japan Institute of Foreign Affairs - Centennial series of American studies, 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-491: Big Sisters, Inc. - Juvenile delinquency, 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-494: Polska Adademia Nauk (Polish Academy of Sciences) - Centre of Bibliography and Scientific Documentation, 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-498: United States Book Exchange, Inc., 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - "L57-504: Institute for Theoretical Physics, University Of Naples", 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-506: American Council for the International Promotion of Democracy - International University of Social Studies of Rome, "Pro Deo", 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-507: Translation and publication of Japanese research materials in the social sciences and humanities, 1957 (Reel L-33)
    See also Ford Foundation Grant 05800198 (PA58-198), International House of Japan, "GENERAL PROGRAM".
  - L57-514: Americans Friends Service Committee - Support of work with American Indians in California and Oregon, 1957 (Reel L-33)
  - L57-525: Harvard University - Center for Advanced Study and Training, Ceylon, 1957 (Reel L-34)
  - L57-526: Wycombe Abbey School, Bucks, England - Support, 1957 (Reel L-34)
  - L57-527: University of Kansas, Governmental Research Center - Survey of urban problems, 1957 (Reel L-34)
  - L57-529: Territorial Hospital, Hawaii - Mental effects of tranquilizing drugs, S.D. Porteus, 1957 (Reel L-34)
  - L57-531: Ford Foundation - Survey of Ford Foundation opportunities in Latin America, 1957 (Reel L-34, Reel L-35)
    See also: Ford Foundation Project file C-336, Yale University, Support for exploration of development activities in Latin America; and Ford Foundation, Fund File "V", Program in Latin America.
  - L57-532: Pilot study and educational program on employment of youth, 1957 (Reel L-35)
  - L57-533: Conference of Professors, plan for recruiting younger men with business experience to college, 1957 (Reel L-35)
  - L57-534: Northwestern University - "The Library of Living Philosophers", 1957 (Reel L-35)
  - L57-536: Contribution to Flaming Sword Monument, Second Division Memorial, 1957 (Reel L-35)
  - L57-537: Support for first national congress, Catholic International Congress of Chicago, 1957 (Reel L-35)
  - L57-539: Publication of theoretical studies in psychology, Long Island University, 1957 (Reel L-35)
  - L57-540: Cultural Foundation of the Philippines, Paul Manglapus, 1957 (Reel L-35)
  - L57-541: Problem of training Americans for overseas service, especially in technical assistance and Overseas Development Programs, 1957 (Reel L-35)
    See also Ford Foundation Log file, L62-673, Training American personnel in development economics, particularly for overseas assignments.
  - L57-548: University of Michigan, Center for Japanese Studies - Support for research on Japanese-American household and community patterns, Richard K. Beardsley, 1957 (Reel L-35)
    See also Ford Foundation Log file, L58-416, Survey of anthropology in Japan.
  - L57-565: Research Institute of Humanistic Science, Kyoto University, Japan - Problems of international communications, 1957 (Reel L-35)
  - L57-567: League of Oregon Cities - National Council of Juvenile Judges, 1957 (Reel L-35)
  - L57-568: Boys Republic, California - Extension of Boys Republic services to youth, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-575: Northwestern University - Training of opera singers, directors, and conductors, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-585: Virginia Museum of Fine Arts - Theatre project, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-594: Advisors for Burma Educational Inquiry Committee, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-596: Global World Series of Baseball, Inc. - General support, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-597: Liberian social science research project (Liberia), 1957 (Reel L-36)
    Includes consultant report "Memorandum on the Need for Social Science Training and Research in the Republic of Liberia", by St. Clair Drake, July 26, 1957, filmed in Section 3.
  - L57-599: Demonstration project on prevention of juvenile delinquency and related social ills, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-610: Study of labor relations in the public service, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-612: Baltimore City Hospitals - Research program in the field of aging, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-613: Support for a center for Anglo-American studies and conferences, Ditchley Park, Oxfordshire, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-618: National Planning Association - Support for committee on security through arms control, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-621: Study of university extension in the United States, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-625: Institute Oud-Poelgeest, Netherlands - General support, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-633: University of California, College of Agriculture, Agricultural Experiment Station - "Strengthening Graduate Training in Agricultural Economics for Foreign Students, with Special Reference to Countries of the Mediterranean Basin and Others with Similar Conditions and Problems", 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-634: Baker Guidance Center - Research project, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-638: American Book Publishers Council - Study of the book industry, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-641: Support for third east-west philosophers conference, University of Hawaii, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-651: Australian Broadcasting Commission - Farm Broadcasting, and television to aid world's peace, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-677: University of Miami, School of Medicine, Jackson Memorial Hospital - Institute of Gerontology, 1957 (Reel L-36)
  - L57-681:Ford Foundation, William Pincus - Recruitment of personnel as political executives in the public service, 1957 (Reel L-37)
  - L57-691: International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources - Conservation of tropics, 1957 (Reel L-37)
  - L57-694: Support for Boy Scout career day conference, Springfield College, 1957 (Reel L-37)
  - L57-695: World Affairs Council of Northern California - Television program, "Why Do Asians and Americans Have Difficulty Understanding Each Other?", 1957 (Reel L-37)
  - L57-696: "Study of Contemporary China: Re-assessment of a Dilemma"; Howard L. Boorman, Research Project on Men and Politics in Modern China, 1957 (Reel L-37)
  - L57-702: Denver Art Museum - contemporary visual arts, 1957 (Reel L-37)
  - L57-707: Gen. Sikorski Historical Institute, London - Sending publications to institutions and libraries of Poland, 1957 (Reel L-37)
  - L57-711: University of Exeter - Capital funds for development, 1957 (Reel L-37)
  - L57-713: Indiana University, Bloomington - Sinological and Japanological Index project, index of Chinese and Japanese literature, 1957 (Reel L-37)
  - L57-714: Greater Boston Economic Study Committee - Support, 1957 (Reel L-37)
  - L57-715: University of Hong Kong, University Press - Support for publications, 1957 (Reel L-37)
  - L57-741: Ford Foundation - Appointment of Consultants re: Training for Overseas Service, 1957 (Reel L-37)
    Consultants: Robert Knapp, Benjamin D. Paul, Egbert S. Wengbert, William T. Phillips. Includes: "Report on Conference on Training Americans for Overseas Service", New York, Ford Foundation, November 3-5, 1960, by William T. Phillips; and "Research and Training for International Development", Report to the Ford Foundation, August 1961, by Egbert Wengbert.
  - L57-745: Louvain University - Research on the common market, 1957 (Reel L-37)
  - L57-748: Dallas Theater Center - Support, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-751: Mental Health Research Fund, University of Glasgow - support for center of psychiatric research, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-753: Public Management Research Institute - Experience and benefits received by American citizens through overseas employment with foreign assistance programs, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-755: First Golden Age Industry Inc. - Providing continued productive work to able-bodies retirees, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-763: University of Wisconsin - Juvenile delinquency problem, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-769: Ford Foundation, Beirut, Lebanon field office - Library training in Syria, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-771: Denver Public Schools - Plan for awards to outstanding elementary school teachers, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-775: National Conference of Forty Plus Clubs of the United States - Support, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-791: Foundation for Research on human Behavior - Support, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-795: Columbia University Press - Legal information for social workers, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-796: University of Montreal - Research on social organization of Montreal, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-802: Senior Social Service of America, Inc. - Support, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-808: Johns Hopkins University and Goucher College - Cooperative program in the fine arts, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-810: Michigan State University - Civic education program, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-815: St. Anne's Convent, Secunderabad, Deccan, India - Support, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-817: Col. Charles F. Densford, USAF - Military service promotion system, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-818: United States Federation of Justice - Support, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-819: Brooklyn Museum - Loan exhibition of the art of India, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-822: Refrigeration Research Foundation - Preservation of Native American cultures, including Hopi Indians, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-829: Music Academy of the West - Support for an academy of advanced musical studies, 1957 (Reel L-38)
  - L57-831: Hans W. Weigert, Georgetown University - Study of foreign policy concepts of the labor parties and unions in European countries, 1957 (Reel L-38)